In this lesson, we're going to take a look at updating an existing endpoint.
在这节课 我们将学习如何更新现有的端点
Suppose that you had already constructed a model and deployed it,
假设你已经构建并部署了一个模型
and that deployed model is now being used in an application somewhere.
某个应用正在使用这个部署的模型
You might later on need to change the model,
之后 你可能想要更改模型
but want to do so in a way that didn't
但是不希望干扰
interrupt availability to whatever app was using it.
应用使用该模型
SageMaker provides functionality that allows you to do this and not have any downtime.
SageMaker 提供了更新模型的功能 并且不会中断服务
In addition we're going to look a little bit closer at
此外 我们将详细了解
the low-level way of creating endpoint configurations,
创建端点配置的低阶方法
as this will allow us some more flexibility and let
这样可以增加灵活性
us build some slightly more sophisticated endpoints.
并构建更复杂的端点
For example, we'll take a look at creating
例如 我们将学习如何创建
an endpoint that sends data to multiple different models.
向多个不同模型发送数据的端点
This might be helpful, for example,
这样可能很有用
when doing an AB test.
例如在进行 A/B 测试时
Along the way we will also be using a mixture of
在此过程中 我们将在 SageMaker 中
the high and low level approaches to creating things inside of SageMaker.
混合使用高阶和低阶创建方法
This can be helpful in your own work because
这样在你自己日后使用 SageMaker 时很有帮助
the high-level approach is really convenient in some cases,
因为高阶方法在某些情形下很有用
but in others, you may need the flexibility of the low-level approach.
但是有时候低阶方法可以带来灵活性
To start with, we're going to look at the Boston Housing dataset again,
首先 我们将再次查看 Boston Housing 数据集
and as we've done before in other notebooks,
与之前在其他 notebook 中一样
we will begin by creating an XGBoost model
我们首先将创建一个 XGBoost 模型
that models the median cost of a house in the Boston area.
它会预测波士顿地区的房价中位数
We, of course, import all of the necessary modules including all the SageMaker ones,
导入所有必要的模块 包括所有 SageMaker 模块
then we load in the data,
然后加载数据
split it up into training validation and testing datasets,
拆分成训练 验证和测试集
save that data to our local notebook instance,
将数据保存到本地 notebook 实例中
upload it to S3,
并上传到 S3
and then we go off and train a model.
然后训练模型
To do that remember first we create an estimator object,
首先创建一个 estimator 对象
which uses the XGBoost container for training.
它会使用 XGBoost 容器进行训练
We then set hyperparameters specific to that algorithm and then we
然后为该算法设置超参数
call fit to fit our model to the training and validation data.
调用 fit() 将模型拟合到训练和验证数据上
Now, the result of calling the fit method is that model artifacts have been created.
现在 调用 fit() 方法后的结果是创建了模型工件
However, the model itself has not yet been
但是模型本身还没有创建
created and when using the high level approach,
在使用高阶方法时
the model won't get created unless it needs to be.
模型不会创建 除非需要创建
For example, if you create a transformation object or if you deploy the model.
例如 在创建转换对象或部署模型时
Since we want to have more control over the deployed model,
因为我们想进一步控制部署的模型
we're going to create our own model using the low-level approach.
所以将使用低阶方法创建我们自己的模型
So, to do that we set up the data structure that
设置好数据结构
describes which containers should be used for inference,
指定推理应该使用的容器
and in addition points to the model artifacts that were created earlier.
并指向之前创建的模型工件
Once we've done that we can ask SageMaker to create the model,
然后要求 SageMaker 创建模型
and once we have a model we can create an endpoint configuration.
有了模型之后 我们可以创建端点配置
Now, this is the same sort of endpoint configuration that you've seen before,
这个端点配置与之前看到的一样
where we only have a single production variant and we call that variant XGB model.
只有一个生产变体 并且称为 XGB-Model
Once we have an endpoint configuration,
有了端点配置后
we can ask SageMaker to create an endpoint with those properties.
要求 SageMaker 使用这些属性创建一个端点
Once that's done we can test our endpoint to make sure that it's working.
然后测试端点 确保一切能运行
First, we serialize the input data and then send it off to our endpoint.
首先序列化输入数据 然后发送给端点
The resulting response we can look at and like
我们可以查看生成的响应
most things in SageMaker the result is a JSON object,
与 SageMaker 中的大多数结果一样 这里的结果也是JSON 对象
which from a Python perspective,
从 Python 的角度来看
might be thought of as a dictionary object.
可以看做字典对象
This response object contains a bunch of information about the results of our model,
这个 response 对象包含关于模型结果的大量信息
in particular it tells us the format of the data that was returned,
它告诉我们返回的数据的格式
it tells us the name of the production variant that our data was sent to.
向其发送数据的生产变体的名称
Now, in this particular case our endpoint only ever sent data to a single model,
对我们来说 端点仅向一个模型发送数据
so we should expect that this is the variant that the data was sent to,
所以这就是向其发送数据的变体
and we have a body object,
这是 body 对象
which is a streaming object.
它是一个 streaming 对象
In order to access the contents of a streaming object,
为了访问 streaming 对象的内容
we need to first read it in,
我们需要首先读取它
and once we've read it in we have a bitstream.
读取后 是一个比特流
Since we know that our result should be an actual string,
因为我们知道结果应该是实际的字符串
we need to convert that bit stream
所以需要将比特流转换成字符串
into a string which we can use the decode method to do.
可以使用 decode() 方法转换
The result is almost 40,
结果约为 40
which is not super close to the true result,
与真实结果并非很接近
but it's close enough.
但是也接近了
Now, we are going to use the XGBoost model a little more later on,
稍后我们还会使用 XGBoost 模型的
but for now we can shut down the endpoint that we created.
但是暂时先关闭创建的端点
Next, we're going to create a second model.
接下来我们将创建第二个模型